是。
發現。
未取消。
立法會主席。
我已經講咗咧。
誒，我有規，唔好意思啊。
美國總統已經簽署咗呢個法律。
一次會議，而議程上嘅十二項法案必須喺今次會議上處理。
石禮謙議員就政府賬目委員會係鄭松泰議員。
然而，一如大家所知，美國總統係已經簽署有關法律。
所以唔係迫切到係一定要喺今次會議上去辯論，石禮謙議員。
誒，鄭松泰議員，我明白你要求辯論嘅事宜係備受各界關注。
基於上述嘅考慮咧，我裁定鄭松泰議員提出嘅議案並不符合議事規則第十六個會議條嘅規定，我不批准你嘅要求。
民生嘅利益嘅，所以我根據咧議事規則嘅十六括弧二條，希望能夠係得到批准，係進行呢一個係關於香港被取消特殊待遇地位嘅議案進行辯論，希望主席能夠考慮。
誒，唔該，主席。係。咁喺清晨嘅時間咧，美國總統簽署行政指令，係取消咗香港嘅特殊待遇。咁亦都指出香港嘅自由咧係同埋權利被奪去啦，香港冇能力同自由市場競爭。我認為咧，呢個講法咧係嚴重影響香港長遠嘅社會經濟同埋同埋。
況且有關嘅事宜咧，議員仍然可以透過唔同渠道作出跟進，而無需有必要喺今次立法會會議上以休會待續議案嘅形式係進行辯論。一如議員所知啊，今次會議係本屆立法會最後。
and。
主席。
within a thirty-minute hearing from.
are chosen for short hearings in the present report.
They are Chapter Three on Employees Retaining Board.
Sports Federation and Olympic Committee of Hong Kong, China.
Out of the eight chapters covered by the director of audits' report.
namely， management of funding for sports development through the Arts and Sport Development Fund.
invited to explain publicly their measures taken and answer follow-up questions from members.
三章涉及issues，which have been repeatedly identified in previous director audits reports.
Number 474, the committee has decided to conduct detailed investigation on two chapters.
Each selected chapter, the relevant bureau departments and organisations preserve.
Before I speak, I like to thank each and every member of the Public Accounts Committee for their hard work during the last four years.
Now I start my report. On behalf of the Public Accounts Committee, I have the honour to table our report number 74.
With a view to enhancing government accountability, the committee has also adopted a new arrangement by conducting short hearings on some of these chapters.
The committee has studied the other six chapters by first asking the parties to provide written replies on their measures to address the inadequacies raised in the director of audit report.
second。
The committee finds such a.
held detailed investigation.
regarding the two chapters for which the committee has.
一國家體育協會，發展足球喺香港。
They have a few things in common. I will highlight four points.
First, they are about sports development in Hong Kong.
for the first chapter about funding for sports development through arts and sport development fund.
find such arrangement very useful and effective in raising public awareness of the work of the government.
委員會有put in quite a lot of efforts examining the operation and governance of Hong Kong Football Association (HKFA).
Both organisation receive substantial funding from the government, and they have to ensure that money is spent in a value for money manner.
Chapter six on management of insolventy services and Chapter seven on management of short-term tenancies by the Lands Department.
for the second chapter, there's mainly on the work of the Sports Federation and Olympic Committee of Hong Kong, China, the National Olympic Committee of Hong Kong, China.
And a five-year plan from two thousand and one five to two thousand and two zero, a new five-year plan has been prepared by the HKFA for the administration's consideration.
For HKFA funding has been provided from the Sports Development Fund to launch the Phoenix projects on football development from 2011 to 2015.
From the start, the committee wishes to stress that both HKFA and the Olympic Committee must preserve its autonomy and resist all pressures of any kind, which may prevent them from complying with the Olympic Charter.
Third.
One of the most.
to two hundred two one。
Achievement have been.
The committee strongly urges.
委員會考慮，H.K.F.A.總體。
to the best, and to be described as disappointing.
overall performance from a value for money perspective.
在這 regard，它反映，政府失敗，未能密切監察HKFA。
委員會 finds the governance of both organisation had room for improvement.
In two hundred one seven to two hundred one eight, the total government funding amounted to more than thirty four million dollars.
Disappointing examples was the was that the audit committee, standing committee of the HKFA, which is responsible for the important task to monitor.
委員會 finds it appalling and inexcusable about the instances instances of non-compliances, irregularities and inadequacies relating to the governance of HKFA.
and review the effectiveness of HKFA internal audit function was not formed from July 2015 to June 2019. This is ridiculous.
The Hong Kong community and local football fans have high expectation of HKFA to raise the standard of football in Hong Kong, as well as the ranking of Hong Kong football teams. However,
for the Olympic Committee, the total amount of funding in two hundred and eighteen to two hundred and nine was around thirty nine million. The Home Affairs Bureau, which also increased its recurrent subvention to the Olympic Committee from twenty million last year to forty million in two thousand and two.
Each way to take.
at the committee's public hearings.
strong resentment and finds it unacceptable.
looking manner, I will call on the administration to ensure.
這是最後委員會報告，第六立法議會。
As revealed in the directors' audit report and at public hearings.
One of the most striking example was that representatives of the Olympic Committee.
委員會強烈 urge 奧林匹克委員會 to review its athlete selection and review processes.
One of the deficiency is that the select in selecting athletes to participate in the 18th Asian Games.
措施， to rectify various non-compliances, deficiencies and irregularities expeditiously.
The Hong Kong Home Affairs Bureau, which is responsible for monitoring the use of funding by HKMA under the Sport Development Fund, should consider measures to assist HKMA to improve its governance.
The selection committee has considered factors such as the athlete is a member of the relay team or a holder of Hong Kong Sport Institute scholarship, and the selection committee had not formally announced these factors to the athletes and the public beforehand.
For the Olympic Committee, the committee expresses alarm and strong resentment and finds it unacceptable that the Olympic Committee's athlete selection process and system, for international games which have been used for over a decade, had deficiencies and irregularities.
making reference to overseas practices. Fourth, the committee considers that the representatives of the relevant bureau, department and government-funded organisation should attach more importance to the director of audit report, as well as to make better preparation for their.
Have been seen as answering the committee's question evasively, providing inconsistent and multi-version answers to the same question, as well as providing incomplete information taken out of context. On this, the committee expresses alarm and.
looking back at the past four years, the committee has conducted 53 public hearings on 21 subjects and published 14 reports. I would like to stress that the conclusion and recommendation are made by the committee in a constructive spirit and for
或的 bureau department and government funded organisation.
could learn the lessons from the committee's report as well as the director of audits' reports.
謝偉俊議員就議事規則委員會二零一九年十月至。
Last but not the least, to the Legislative Council Secretariat for their hard work. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
They should implement necessary measures well in advance to prevent the occurrence of the non-compliances, deficiency and irregularities identified. Lastly, I wish to record my appreciation.
Of the contribution made by members of this committee, as I have started when I begin the speech, our gratitude also goes to the witnesses who attended the hearing. Health Body Committee. I would like to express our gratitude to the Director of Audit and his colleague for their unfailing report support.